# **Joseph Garrett Corbin**

jgarrettcorbin@gmail.com • 804-399-1576

github.com/platevoltage • linkedin.com/in/garrett-corbin-7a7777227/ • jgarrettcorbin.com

# **Summary Statement**

Full stack web developer who will help your company succeed by completing projects on time and under budget. Trained by UC Berkeley's Extension program, I worked on several projects and collaborated with different teams using agile practices (links below).

# **Projects**

### Professional Portfolio - Built from the ground up to showcase projects.

Repo: https://github.com/platevoltage/portfolio-v4.0-react

Live link: https://jgarrettcorbin.com

- · Built using the React.js library and Typescript.
- Content is easily added or removed using a JSON configuration file.

### RGB Strip Controller - Controlling your LED light strips made easy.

Repo: https://github.com/platevoltage/RGB-strip-controller Live link: https://platevoltage.github.io/RGB-strip-controller/

- · React front end that is served directly from an Espressif Wifi-enabled microcontroller using REST API.
- · Back end build using PlatformIO and ESP WebServer libraries.
- · Utilizes LittleFS to store configuration between power cycles.

### Story Factory - A full stack social media based creative writing app.

Repo: https://github.com/platevoltage/Story-Factory

Live link: https://story-factory.home.jgarrettcorbin.com

- Led the team on the design and functionality of this application.
- React.js app backed by Node.js, MongoDB via Mongoose, and deployed on Heroku.
- · Uses Bcrypt and JSON Web Tokens for authentication.

# **Relevant Work Experience**

#### **Automation Tech**

Wood You Recycle - Albuquerque, NM 2016-2019

- Programmed Siemens PLCs, designed custom controllers using Atmel microcontrollers and EAGLE.
- Used Linux and Raspberry Pi to develop a monitoring system, decreasing responsibilities for the operator.

#### R&D and Installation

Fossil Free Fuel - Pittsburgh, PA 2009-2011

- Designed a digital controller based around the Atmel 328p microcontroller and a character LCD display for operating and monitoring fuel system temperatures.
- Designed and installed vegetable oil fuel systems in diesel cars and trucks.

## **Education**

### University of California, Berkeley

2021-2022

- · Full Stack Web Development course.
- Used Node.js and Express.js to build server backends.
- Became proficient in libraries and frameworks including React, Bootstrap, and jQuery.
- · Worked productively on a remote team using Zoom and Github Projects.

### Skills

Javascript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, Node.js, React, Electron, Angular, MySQL/PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Apollo GraphQL, Express.js, Linux/UNIX, Embedded C++, IoT